Natia Lollie

Portfolio: natialollie.success-way.co Github: github.com/natiaLollie Linkedin: linkedin/in/natialollie Email: natialollie.developer@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Engineer with a deep interest in JavaScript and Python, and a primary focus on integrating Artificial Intelligence and Computer Vision. Demonstrated expertise and a proven track record of developing successful front-end and back-end web systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The University of Texas at San Antonio edX

Jul 2022 - Present

Full Stack, UXUI Instructor Teaching Assistant

Remote

- Bridged the gap between understanding the intricacies of website development, systematic processes, programming solutions, and the core principles of HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery for creating impactful website experiences. The student cohort graduated with a 100% success rate.
- Instructor (Sub) for George Washington University, successfully teaching 17 students the fundamentals of JavaScript and JQuery for website applications.

The University of Houston

Jan 2020 - Sep 2021

Web Developer II, Lead

Houston, TX

- Managed cross-departmental relationships, working closely with the information technology department, while serving as the lead for website champions, resulting in a 30% increase in university donors and engagement.
- Served as design and technical leader for the launch of four multi-user sites with a primary responsibility for maintenance of 8 departmental websites and producing documentation outlining project goals, timelines, debugging, and conducting system audits. Provided departmental training for technical software such as Thankview.
- Developed, designed, and deployment of over 8 new responsive web pages and microsites for the University Advancement CMS and WordPress websites, including the University's "Billion Dollar 'Here We Go' Campaign".

Sourceway E-Commerce

Dec 2016 – Jan 2020

Front-End Web Developer

Remote

- Successfully rebranded the company image to bring in over \$141,000 in sales at re-launch. Visually communicated and proposed ideas that utilize current web design trends and UXUI best practices to design and develop the store's (re) branding kit, website, and product templates.
- Applied front-end programming languages to fully customize and launch the website within a strict deadline. Incorporated HTML/CSS, PHP, and Javascript to override WordPress defaults, develop a custom theme, and minimize the use of plugins; to reduce page load times by 10%.

ROBOTICS HIGHLIGHT

• **ALTO-R** - A Little Trainable Robot, Recyclable - Integration of software development (Python) and machine learning techniques to identify recyclable objects. I assembled it using hardware and electronic components.

EDUCATION

Samsung
Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

Dec 2022 – May 2023

Remote

Special Recognition: Samsung <u>USA</u> and <u>Global</u> Newsrooms

Sam Houston State University

Aug 2011 – Dec 2016

Bachelor of Science, 3.6 GPA

Huntsville, TX

Honors: Alpha Lambda Delta National Honor Society, Academic Dean's List (Spring 2016)

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, Git, WordPress
- Interest: Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Web Development, Computer Vision, Robotics